我想今天开始，我们要谈谈Google文件的GFS
I'd like to get started today we're
gonna talk about GFS the Google file
我们今天阅读的系统论文，这将是第一篇
system paper we read for today
and this will be the first of a number
在本课程中，我们将讨论各种案例研究
of different sort of case studies we'll
talk about in this course about how to
建立大型存储系统，所以更大的话题是大型存储的原因
be build big storage systems so the
larger topic is big storage the reason
是事实证明存储是关键的抽象，如果您知道
is the storage is turned out to be a key
abstraction you might you know if you
不知道你可能会想像可能有各种各样的
didn't know already you might imagine
that there could be all kinds of
不同，您知道可能要用于的重要抽象
different you know important
abstractions you might want to use for
分布式系统，但事实证明，简单的存储接口只是
distributed systems but it's turned out
that a simple storage interface is just
非常有用且极为笼统，因此许多想法已经消失
incredibly useful and extremely general
and so a lot of the thought that's gone
建立分布式系统已进入设计存储
into building distributed systems has
either gone into designing storage
系统或设计在其下假设某种其他功能的其他系统
systems or designing other systems that
assume underneath them some sort of
表现良好的大型分布式存储系统，所以我们
reasonably well behaved big just
distributed storage system so we're
会非常在意您如何设计一个好的界面
going to care a lot about how the you
know how to design a good interface to a
大型存储系统以及如何设计存储系统的内部结构
big storage system and how to design the
innards of the storage system so it has
您当然知道行为良好，这就是为什么我们阅读本文只是为了获得
good behavior you know of course that's
why we're reading this paper just to get
本文的起点还涉及很多主题，这些主题将
a start on that the this paper also
touches on a lot of themes that will
大量介绍并行性能容错复制
come up a lot in a tube for parallel
performance fault tolerance replication
和一致性，本文就是这样合理
and consistency and this paper is as
such things go reasonably
直观易懂，这也是一本很好的系统论文
straightforward and easy to understand
it's also a good systems paper it sort
讨论了从硬件到软件的所有问题
of talks about issues all the way from
the hardware to the software that
最终使用该系统，这是一个成功的现实世界设计，因此它说
ultimately uses the system and it's a
successful real world design so it says
你知道学术会议上发表的学术论文，但它描述了
you know academic paper published in an
academic conference but it describes
真正成功的东西，在现实世界中使用了很长时间
something that really was successful and
used for a long time in the real world
所以我们知道我们在谈论的是一个很好的
so we sort of know that we're talking
about something that is it's a good a
好有用的设计好吧，所以在我谈论GFS之前，我想
good useful design okay so before I'm
gonna talk about GFS I want to sort of
谈论分布式存储系统的空间
talk about the space of distributed
storage systems a little bit
首先设置场景，为什么很难
set the scene so first why is it hard
实际上很多事情是正确的，但是对于2/4，有一种特殊的
it's actually a lot to get right but for
a 2/4 there's a particular sort of
对于许多系统而言，这种叙事往往会很多
narrative that's gonna come up quite a
lot for many systems often the starting
人们设计这类大型分布式系统或大型存储的关键
point for people designing these sort of
big distributed systems or big storage
系统是他们希望获得巨大的综合性能并能够驾驭
systems is they want to get huge
aggregate performance be able to harness
数百台机器的资源，以便完成大量工作
the resources of hundreds of machines in
order to get a huge amount of work done
因此，起点通常是性能，并且您知道是否开始
so the sort of starting point is often
performance and you know if you start
有一个自然的下一个想法是，我们要把我们的数据分成大量
there a natural next thought is well
we're gonna split our data over a huge
数量的服务器，以便能够并行读取许多服务器，因此我们
number of servers in order to be able to
read many servers in parallel so we're
会得到，如果您在许多服务器上分片，通常称为分片
gonna get and that's often called
sharding if you shard over many servers
数百或数千台服务器，如果
hundreds or thousands of servers you're
just gonna see constant faults right if
您有成千上万的服务器，总会出现故障，因此我们
you have thousands of servers there's
just always gonna be one down so we
默认值是每天每小时发生一次，我们需要自动
defaults are just every day every hour
occurrences and we need automatic
涉及人类的周末并修复此故障，我们需要自动
weekend of humans involved and fixing
this fault we need automatic
容错系统，因此导致容错能力是最强的
fault-tolerant systems so that leads to
fault tolerance the among the most
获得容错的有效方法是复制，只需保留两个或三个
powerful ways to get fault tolerance is
with replication just keep two or three
或其中任何一个数据副本失败，您可以使用另一个副本，因此我们希望
or whatever copies of data one of them
fails you can use another one so we want
如果您有两个复制，则具有导致复制的容忍度
to have tolerance that leads to
replication if you have replication two
复制数据，然后确定是否不小心会丢失数据
copies the data then you know for sure
if you're not careful they're gonna get
不同步，所以您认为是数据的两个副本
out of sync and so what you thought was
two replicas of the data where you could
如果您不小心，可以互换使用其中一种来容忍错误
use either one interchangeably to
tolerate faults if you're not careful
您最终得到的是两个几乎相同的数据副本
what you end up with is two almost
identical replicas of the data that's
就像根本不完全是复制品一样，您获得的回报取决于哪一个
like not exactly replicas at all and
what you get back depends on which one
你说话，所以开始看起来可能有点
you talk to so that's starting to maybe
look a little bit
应用程序使用起来很棘手，所以如果我们有复制操作，我们可能会感到奇怪
tricky for applications to use so if we
have replication we risk weird
当然，巧妙的设计可以消除不一致和
inconsistencies of course clever design
you can get rid of inconsistency and
使数据看起来非常正常，但如果这样做，几乎总是需要
make the data look very well-behaved but
if you do that it almost always requires
所有不同服务器之间的额外工作和额外的选择
extra work and extra sort of chitchat
between all the different servers and
网络中的客户端会降低性能，因此如果需要一致性
clients in the network that reduces
performance so if you want consistency
您为性能低下付出的代价我当然不是我们最初的目标
you pay for with low performance I which
is of course not what we originally
当然希望这是绝对的，您可以构建非常高的性能
hoping for of course this is an absolute
you can build very high performance
系统，但是尽管如此，设计还是不可避免的
systems but nevertheless there's this
sort of inevitable way that the design
这些系统发挥作用，并导致最初目标之间的紧张关系
of these systems play out and it results
in a tension between the original goals
表现和那种认识，如果你想要好的
of performance and the sort of
realization that if you want good
一致性，您将为此付出代价，如果您不想为此付出代价，那么您
consistency you're gonna pay for it and
if you don't want to pay for it then you
不得不遭受某种异常行为的困扰有时我会提出这个建议
have to suffer with sort of anomalous
behavior sometimes I'm putting this up
因为我们将在许多系统中多次看到此循环
because we're gonna see this this loop
many times for many of the systems we
看我们看的人是我们很少愿意或不愿意支付
look we look at people are we're rarely
willing to or happy about paying the
很好的一致性的全部成本，好的，所以您知道带来一致性后，我会
full cost of very good consistency ok so
you know with brought a consistency I'll
在本课程的后面再讨论更多关于我所说的良好一致性的确切含义
talk more later in the course about more
exactly what I mean by good consistency
但您可以将强一致性或良好一致性视为我们想要的
but you can think of strong consistency
or good consistency as being we want to
构建一个系统，其对应用程序或客户端的行为类似于
build a system whose behavior to
applications or clients looks just like
您会期望与单个服务器进行对话，好了，我们将为您打造
you'd expect from talking to a single
server all right we're gonna build you
知道数百台机器中的系统，但具有理想的强一致性
know systems out of hundreds of machines
but a kind of ideal strong consistency
如果只有一台服务器带有一个副本，那么您将获得的模型
model would be what you'd get if there
was just one server with one copy of the
数据一次只能做一件事，所以这很强大
data doing one thing at a time so this
is kind of a strong
一致性是一种考虑强一致性的直观方法，因此您
consistency kind of intuitive way to
think about strong consistency so you
可能认为您有一台服务器，我们假设这是一台单线程服务器
might think you have one server we'll
assume that's a single-threaded server
并且它一次处理一个来自客户端的请求，那就是
and that it processes requests from
clients one at a time and that's
重要，因为可能有很多客户端同时发送请求
important because there may be lots of
clients sending concurrently requests
进入服务器并查看一些当前请求，它选择一个或另一个去
into the server and see some current
requests it picks one or the other to go
首先，请原谅请求完成，然后再原谅网
first and excuse that request to
completion then excuse the nets so for
存储服务器，或者您知道服务器上有磁盘，这意味着
storage servers or you know the server's
got a disk on it and what it means to
处理一个请求，这是一个您可能知道正在写的写请求
process a request is it's a write
request you know which might be writing
一个项目，或者可能是增加的，我的意思是，如果它是一个变异，则增加一个项目
an item or may be increment and I mean
incrementing an item if it's a mutation
那么我们要走了，我们有一些数据表，您也许知道索引
then we're gonna go and we have some
table of data and you know maybe index
通过键和值，我们将更新此表，如果请求
by keys and values and we're gonna
update this table and if the request
进来阅读，我们只是要知道将写入数据拉出
comes in and to read we're just gonna
you know pull the write data out of the
列出这里的规则之一，使其表现良好，就是每个
table one of the rules here that sort of
makes this well-behaved is that each is
服务器确实确实在我们简化的模型借口中执行请求
that the server really does execute in
our simplified model excuse to request
一次一个，并且该请求看到的数据反映了所有以前的数据
one at a time and that requests see data
that reflects all the previous
按顺序进行操作，以便按顺序执行写入操作以及服务器进程
operations in order so if a sequence of
writes come in and the server process
他们以某种顺序排列，然后当您阅读时，您会看到一种您知道自己有价值的东西
them in some order then when you read
you see the sort of you know value you
会期望如果一次发生的写操作的行为是
would expect if those writes that
occurred one at a time the behavior this
仍然不是很简单，有一些你知道有一些
is still not completely straightforward
there's some you know there's some
您必须花费至少一秒钟思考的事情，例如，如果
things that you have to spend at least a
second thinking about so for example if
我们有一堆客户，一个客户发出价值X的写信，并希望
we have a bunch of clients and client
one issues a write of value X and wants
将其设置为一个，同时客户端两个发出相同的权利
it to set it to one and at the same time
client two issues the right of the same
值，但想要将其设置为其他相同的键，但希望将其设置为
value but wants to set it to a different
the same key but wants to set it to a
发生一些不同的价值吧，假设客户三
different value right
something happens let's say client three
在这些写入完成读取后读取并获得一些结果或客户端三
reads and get some result or client
three after these writes complete reads
得到一些结果客户机四读X并且得到一些也得到结果
get some result client four
reads X and get some also gets a result
那两个客户应该看到什么结果
so what results should the two clients
see yeah
好，这是一个很好的问题，所以我在这里假设的是那个客户
well that's a good question so these
what I'm assuming here is that client
一个倾向于同时启动这些请求，因此如果我们正在监视
one inclined to launch these requests at
the same time so if we were monitoring
网络，我们会看到两个请求同时发送到服务器
the network we'd see two requests
heading to the server at the same time
然后一段时间后，服务器会响应它们
and then sometime later the server would
respond to them
所以这里实际上没有足够的空间来说明客户是否愿意
so there's actually not enough here to
be able to say whether the client would
收据将首先处理第一个请求，该请求的订单不足
receipt would process the first request
first which order there's not enough
这里告诉服务器处理的顺序，当然还有
here to tell which order the server
processes them in and of course if it
首先处理此请求，然后处理或
processes this request first then that
means or it processes the right with
值到秒，这意味着后续读取必须查看在哪里
value to second and that means that
subsequent reads have to see to where is
服务器碰巧首先处理了这个请求，而第二个则是
it the server happened to process this
request first and this one's second that
意味着结果值最好是1，而这两个请求是
means the resulting value better be one
and these these two requests and see
所以，我只是为了说明这一点，即使是简单的
what so I'm just putting this up to sort
of illustrate that even in a simple
系统存在不确定性，您不一定可以从跟踪结果中看出来
system there's ambiguity you can't
necessarily tell from trace of what went
进入服务器或应该显示出来的全部信息是，
into the server or what should come out
all of you can tell is that some set of
结果与可能的执行结果一致或不一致，因此可以肯定
results is consistent or not consistent
with a possible execution so certainly
有一些完全错误的结果，我们可以看到，如果客户端3
there's some completely wrong results we
can see go by it you know if client 3
看到2，然后客户4，我敢打赌最好也看到它，因为我们的模型是
sees a 2 then client 4 I bet had better
see it too also because our model is
在第二个权利之后，你知道爬树，这是两个
well after the second right you know
climb trees these are two that means
这项权利一定是第二位的，它最好还是仍然必须拥有
this right must have been second and it
still had better be it still has to have
是第一个客户4的第二个权利，所以希望这一切都是
been the second right one client 4 goes
to the date so hopefully all this is
完全简单明了，正如预期的那样，因为
just completely straightforward and just
as expected because it's it's supposed
成为强一致性的直观模型还可以，所以
to be the intuitive model of strong
consistency ok and so the problem with
这当然是单个服务器的容错能力差，如果它
this of course is that a single server
has poor fault tolerance right if it
崩溃或磁盘死机或我们一无所有，因此在
crashes or it's disk dies or something
we're left with nothing and so in the
在分布式系统的真实世界中，我们实际上构建了复制系统，因此
real world of distributed systems we
actually build replicated systems so and
那是所有问题开始泄漏的地方，当我们有第二个
that's where all the problems start
leaking in is when we have a second
复制数据，因此这里必须接近最差的复制设计
copying data so here is what must be
close to the worst replication design
我这样做是为了警告您我们将要寻找的问题
and I'm doing this to warn you of the
problems that we will then be looking
在GFS中可以正常使用，所以这是一个糟糕的复制设计，我们将有两个
for in GFS all right so here's a bad
replication design we're gonna have two
现在，每台服务器都具有数据的完整副本，因此磁盘都是
servers now each with a complete copy of
the data and so on disks that are both
将拥有此键表并重视其直觉，当然是
gonna have this this table of keys and
values the intuition of course is that
我们希望保留这些表，我们希望保持这些表相同，以便
we want to keep these tables we hope to
keep these tables identical so that if
一台服务器发生故障，我们可以从另一台服务器读取或写入数据，因此这意味着
one server fails we can read or write
from the other server and so that means
以某种方式每次写入都必须由服务器和读取双方处理
that somehow every write must be
processed by both servers and reads have
能够由单个服务器处理，否则它不是容错的
to be able to be processed by a single
server otherwise it's not fault tolerant
好的，如果读取必须同时查阅两者，那么我们就无法在失去其中之一的情况下生存
all right if reads have to consult both
and we can't survive the loss of one of
服务器没问题，所以问题会解决的很好，我想我们有客户端1
the servers okay so the problem is gonna
come up well I suppose we have client 1
和客户2，他们两个都想做正确的事，说其中一个要写
and client 2 and they both want to do
these right say one of them gonna write
一个要写两个，所以客户端1要启动它是正确的
one and the other is going to write two
so client 1 is gonna launch it's right
x1 2都是因为我们想同时更新它们和攀登2将要启动
x1 2 both because we want to update both
of them and climb 2 is gonna launch it's
写X所以这里出什么问题了是的我们在这里没有做任何事情
write X so what's gonna go wrong here
yeah yeah we haven't done anything here
确保两个服务器以相同的顺序处理两个请求
to ensure that the two servers process
the two requests in the same order right
这是一个糟糕的设计，因此如果服务器1处理客户端
that's a bad design
so if server 1 processes client ones
首先请求它将以1开头，然后将看到
request first it'll end up it'll start
with a value of 1 and then it'll see
如果服务器2刚好碰到客户端二进制请求并用2覆盖
client twos request and overwrite that
with 2 if server 2 just happens to
通过网络以不同的顺序接收数据包
receive the packets over the network in
a different order it's going to execute
客户2的请求并将其值设置为2，然后它将看到客户的
client 2's requests and set the value to
2 and then then it will see client ones
请求将值设置为1，然后是以后阅读的客户端看到您的客户端
request set the value to 1 and now what
a client a later reading client sees you
知道客户端3是否碰巧从此服务器到达，并且客户端发生
know if client 3 happens to reach from
this server and client for happens to
从另一台服务器到达，然后我们陷入这种可怕的境地
reach from the other server then we get
into this terrible situation where
即使我们采用正确的直观模型，他们也会读取不同的值
they're gonna read different values even
though our intuitive model of a correct
服务人员说，它们随后的读取值都很高，您具有相同的值，这可以
service says they both subsequent reads
hefty you're the same value and this can
以您知道的其他方式出现，假设我们试图通过使客户解决此问题
arise in other ways you know suppose we
try to fix this by making the clients
总是从服务器一读取（如果启动），否则从服务器二读取
always read from server one if it's up
and otherwise server two if we do that
那么如果这种情况发生了，那么为什么四个人都读呢？
then if this situation happened and four
why oh yeah both everybody reads might
看到客户端也可能看到价值，但是服务器突然突然失败，甚至
see client might see value too but a
server one suddenly fails then even
尽管突然没有正确的X值，我们将从2切换为1
though there was no right suddenly the
value for X we'll switch from 2 to 1
因为如果服务器1死了，那就是所有客户助理服务器2否，而仅仅是
because if server 1 died it's all the
clients assistant server 2 no but just
数据中这种神秘的变化与任何权利都不对应
this mysterious change in the data that
doesn't correspond to any right which is
也完全不是这种服务中可能发生的事情
also totally not something that could
have happened in this service simple
服务器模型还可以，所以当然可以修复，修复需要更多
server model all right so of course this
can be fixed the fix requires more
通常是服务器之间或更复杂的地方之间的通信
communication usually between the
servers or somewhere more complexity and
因为不可避免的成本使成本变得越来越复杂
because of the cost of inevitable cost
to the complexity to get strong
一致性，有各种各样的解决方案可以使您变得更好
consistency there's a whole range of
different solutions to get better
一致性和人们认为的整个范围是可接受的水平
consistency and a whole range of what
people feel is an acceptable level of
可接受的一组异常行为中的一致性，这可能是
consistency in an acceptable sort of a
set of anomalous behaviors that might be
在这里透露了有关此灾难性模型的所有问题
revealed all right any questions about
this disastrous model here
好的，那就是您在谈论GFS的原因，关于做GFS的很多想法是
okay that's what you're talking about
GFS a lot of thought about doing GFS was
这样做是为了解决问题，他们的行为更好但不是很完美，所以GFS在哪里
doing is fixing this they had better but
not perfect behavior okay so where GFS
早在2003年就诞生了，当时
came from in 2003 quite a while ago
actually at that time the the web you
知道肯定开始变得非常重要，人们正在建立庞大的
know was certainly starting to be a very
big deal and people are building big
此外，对分布式网站进行了数十年的研究
websites in addition there had been
decades of research into distributed
系统和人们至少在学术水平上知道如何构建所有
systems and people sort of knew at least
at the academic level how to build all
各种系统都具有高度并行的容错能力，但是
kinds of highly parallel fault tolerant
whatever systems but there been very
在行业中很少使用学术思想，但从那时开始
little use of academic ideas in industry
but starting at around the time this
论文发表后，像Google这样的大型网站开始真正建立
paper was published big websites like
Google started to actually build serious
分布式系统，这对像我这样的人来说非常令人兴奋
distributed systems and it was like very
exciting for people like me who were I'm
我很高兴看到一个孩子，看到这些想法在Google当时的实际用途
a kid I'm excited this to see see real
uses of these ideas where Google was
您知道他们有一些庞大的数据集
coming from was you know they had some
vast vast data sets far larger than
可以存储在单个磁盘中，例如网络的整个爬网副本或一点
could be stored in a single disk like an
entire crawl copy of the web or a little
在这篇论文之后，他们有巨大的YouTube视频，他们有类似
bit after this paper they had giant
YouTube videos they had things like the
用于建立搜索索引的中间文件
intermedia files for building a search
index
他们显然还保留了所有Web服务器上的大量日志文件，因此
they also apparently kept enormous log
files from all their web servers so they
以后可以分析它们，以便他们拥有一些大的大数据集
could later analyze them so they had
some big big data sets they used both to
存储它们以及许多磁盘来存储它们，它们需要能够
store them and many many disks to store
them and they needed to be able to
使用MapReduce之类的工具快速处理它们，因此它们需要高速
process them quickly with things like
MapReduce so they needed high speed
可以并行访问这些海量数据，所以他们在寻找什么
parallel access to these vast amounts of
data okay so what they were looking for
一个目标是，事情又快又大，他们还想要一个文件系统
one goal was just that the thing be big
and fast they also wanted a file system
从许多不同的应用程序可以
that was sort of global in the sense
that many different applications could
了解构建大型存储系统的一种方法是您知道自己有一些
特定的应用程序或采矿，您将建立专用的存储
particular application or mining you
build storage sort of dedicated and
量身定制的应用程序，如果下一个办公室的其他人需要
tailored to that application and if
somebody else in the next office needs
大容量存储库，他们可以构建自己的东西
big storage well they can build their
own thing
是的，但是如果您具有通用或某种全局可重用的存储系统
right but if you have a universal or
kind of global reusable storage system
这意味着如果我存储大量数据，您会知道我正在爬网
and that means that if I store a huge
amount of data si you know I'm crawling
网络，您想查看我的已爬网网页，因为我们都
the web and you want to look at my
crawled web web pages because we're all
使用我们都在同一个沙盒中玩，我们都使用相同的存储
using we're all playing in the same
sandbox we're all using the same storage
系统，您可以读取我的文件，但您知道访问控制允许
system you can just read my files you
know maybe access controls permitting so
这个想法是建立一种文件系统，在那里您认识的任何人
the idea was to build a sort of file
system where anybody you know anybody
Google内部可以命名和读取任何文件以允许共享，以便
inside Google could name and read any of
the files to allow sharing in order to
为了获得更大的牢固性，他们需要拆分数据
get a in order to get bigness and
fastness they need to split the data
通过每个文件，GFS会自动将其分割到许多服务器上，以便
through every file will be automatically
split by GFS over many servers so that
只要您能自动进行读写操作
writes and reads would just
automatically be fast as long as you
正在从很多客户那里读取大量文件
were reading from lots and lots of
reading a file from lots of clients you
获得高的总吞吐量，并且还能够针对单个文件执行以下操作：
get high aggregate throughput and also
be able to for a single file be able to
具有比任何单个磁盘大的单个文件，因为我们正在构建
have single files that were bigger than
any single disk because we're building
我们希望数百台服务器中的某些功能能够自动感觉到您的恢复，
something out of hundreds of servers we
want automatic feel your recovery we
不想建立一个系统，每当我们数百台服务器中的一台
don't want to build a system where every
time one of our hundreds of servers a
失败了，有些人不得不去机房，用
fail some human being has to go to the
machine room and do something with the
服务器或使其启动并运行或传输数据或类似的东西
server or to get it up and running or
transfers data or something well this
不只是自我修复，还有一些非目标，例如GFS
isn't just fix itself um there were some
sort of non goals like one is that GFS
旨在在单个数据中心中运行，因此我们不在谈论
was designed to run in a single data
center so we're not talking about
将复制品放置在世界各地，只需一个GFS安装即可
placing replicas all over the world a
single GFS installation just lived in
一个一台数据中心一台大机器在运行，因此要使这种样式的系统正常工作
one one data center one big machine run
so getting this style system to work
副本彼此相距遥远是一个有价值的目标，但
where the replicas are far distant from
each other is a valuable goal but
很难，所以单个数据中心这不是GFS为客户提供的服务
difficult so single data centers this is
not a service to customers GFS was for
由Google工程师编写的应用程序内部使用
internal use by
applications written by Google engineers
所以不是他们不是直接卖掉他们可能要卖掉的东西
so it wasn't they weren't directly
selling this they might be selling
他们在内部使用GFS的服务，但并未直接出售它，因此
services they used GFS internally but
they weren't selling it directly so it's
仅供内部使用，并且它以多种方式量身定制
just for internal use and it was
tailored in a number of ways for big
顺序文件读取和写入有一个完整的域，例如
sequential file reads and writes there's
a whole nother domain like a system of
针对小型数据进行了优化的存储系统，例如银行
storage systems that are optimized for
small pieces of data like a bank that's
持有银行余额的人可能想要一个可以读写数据的数据库
holding bank balances probably wants a
database that can read and write an
更新您知道的100字节记录可以保存人们的银行余额，但是GFS是
update you know 100 byte records that
hold people's bank balances but GFS is
不是那个系统，所以它的确是大容量还是大型容量，您知道TB千兆字节
not that system so it's really for big
or big is you know terabytes gigabytes
一些大的顺序非随机访问
some big sequential not random access
也有一定的批次风味，没有很多
it's also that has a certain batch
flavor there's not a huge amount of
努力使访问延迟非常低，重点是
effort to make access be very low
latency the focus is really on
您知道多兆字节操作的吞吐量
throughput of big you know multi
megabyte operations this paper was
在2003年的sOSP上发表的顶级系统学术会议通常
published at s OSP in 2003 the top
systems academic conference yeah usually
这类会议的论文标准，你知道很多非常新颖的
the standard for papers such conferences
they have you know a lot of very novel
研究本文不一定是该类中的具体思想
research this paper was not necessarily
in that class the specific ideas in this
在当时，它们都不是特别新的东西，例如发行
paper none of them are particularly new
at the time and things like distribution
和分片和容错功能，您知道必须了解
and sharding and fault tolerance were
you know well understood had to had to
提供这些，但是本文描述了一个真正在其中运行的系统
deliver those but this paper described a
system that was really operating in in
大规模使用数十万台更大的机器
use at a far far larger scale hundreds
of thousands of machines much bigger
你们所知道的学者中从未有过这样的事实：
than any you know academics ever built
the fact that it was used in industry
并反映出现实世界中的经验，例如实际上不起作用的东西
and reflected real world experience of
like what actually didn't didn't work
对于必须运行且必须具有成本效益的已部署系统，例如
for deployed systems that had to work
and had to be cost effective also like
极有价值的论文提出了一种相当异端的观点
extremely valuable the paper sort of
proposed a fairly heretical view that it
可以让存储系统具有漂亮的
was okay for the storage system to have
pretty
一致性，我们当时的学术思维是您知道存储
consistency we the academic mindset at
that time was the you know the storage
系统确实应该具有良好的行为，例如构建的重点
system really should have good behavior
like what's the point of building
返回错误数据的系统，例如我糟糕的复制系统
systems that sort of return the wrong
data like my terrible replication system
像为什么这样做为什么不建立系统返回正确的数据正确的数据
like why do that why not build systems
return the right data correct data
而不是现在的错误数据，实际上不能保证退货
instead of incorrect data now with this
paper actually does not guarantee return
正确的数据，您知道希望他们会利用
correct data and you know the hope is
that they take advantage of that in
为了获得更好的性能，我是最后一件有趣的事情
order to get better performance I'm a
final thing that was sort of interesting
关于本文的是它在某种学术论文中对单个硕士的使用
about this paper is its use of a single
master in a sort of academic paper you
可能有一些容错复制的自动故障恢复
probably have some fault-tolerant
replicated automatic failure recovering
大师也许与工作的许多大师分开开放，但本文说
master perhaps many masters with the
work split open um but this paper said
看起来你知道你可以和一个大师一起逃脱，而且效果很好
look you know you they can get away with
a single master and it worked fine well
愤世嫉俗的你知道谁会在网络上注意到一些选票或
cynically you know who's going to notice
on the web that some vote count or
出了点问题，或者如果您现在在搜索引擎上进行搜索，您将知道
something is wrong or if you do a search
on a search engine now you're gonna know
哦，您知道搜索结果中缺少20,000个项目之一
that oh you know like one of 20,000
items is missing from the search results
否则他们的顺序可能不正确，所以还有更多
or they're in the wrong order probably
not so there was just much more
在这类系统中的容忍度要比在银行中要高
tolerance in these kind of systems than
there would like in a bank for incorrect
数据并不意味着所有数据和网站都可能出错，例如
data it doesn't mean that all data and
websites can be wrong like if you're
向人们收取广告展示费用，您最好正确地确定数字，但这是
charging people for ad impressions you
better get the numbers right but this is
除了这些之外，GFS可以发挥作用的一些方式
not really about that in addition some
of the ways in which GFS could serve up
奇数数据可以在应用中得到补偿，例如本文所说的
odd data could be compensated for in the
applications like where the paper says
您知道应用程序应在其数据中附带校验和，并清楚
you know applications should accompany
their data with check sums and clearly
标记记录边界，以便应用程序可以从GFS恢复
mark record boundaries that's so the
applications can recover from GFS
为他们提供服务可能不是正确的数据
serving them maybe not quite the right
data
好的，所以一般的结构，这只是本文的第一图，所以
all right so the general structure and
this is just figure one in the paper so
我们有一堆客户，数百个客户，我们有一个主人
we have a bunch of clients hundreds
hundreds of clients we have one master
尽管可能存在母版的副本，但母版会保留来自
although there might be replicas of the
master the master keeps the mapping from
文件名，基本上可以找到数据的位置，尽管实际上有两个
file names to where to find the data
basically although there's really two
表，然后有一大堆块服务器，也许数百块
tables so and then there's a bunch of
chunk servers maybe hundreds of chunk
每个服务器可能都带有一两张光盘，这里是主机
servers each with perhaps one or two
discs the separation here's the master
就是关于命名和知道块在哪里以及块服务器的全部
is all about naming and knowing where
the chunks are and the chunk servers
存储实际数据，这就像这两个设计的一个不错的方面
store the actual data this is like a
nice aspect of the design that these two
关注点几乎完全彼此分离，可以设计为
concerns are almost completely separated
from each other and can be designed just
主机通过单独的属性分别了解所有文件
separately with separate properties the
master knows about all the files for
主文件会跟踪每个文件的块标识符列表
every file the master keeps track of a
list of chunks chunk identifiers that
包含文件的每个块的连续块为64 MB，所以如果我有
contain the successive pieces that file
each chunk is 64 megabytes so if I have
一个你知道的千兆字节文件，主服务器会知道，也许第一个块是
a you know gigabyte file the master is
gonna know that maybe the first chunk is
存储在这里，第二块存储在这里第三块存储在此处
stored here and the second chunk is
stored here the third chunk is stored
在这里，如果我想读取文件的任何部分，我都需要问主
here and if I want to read whatever part
of the file I need to ask the master oh
哪个服务器漏洞就是那个块，我去与那个服务器交谈并读取该块
which server hole is that chunk and I go
talk to that server and read the chunk
大致来说没事，更准确地说，如果我们要
roughly speaking all right so more
precisely we need to turns out if we're
将要讨论的系统如何关于系统的一致性及其如何
going to talk about how the system about
the consistency of the system and how it
处理错误，我们需要知道主机实际存储在
deals with false we need to know what
the master is actually storing in a
更多细节，以便掌握数据
little bit more detail so the master
data
它有两个我们关心的主表，一个有地图文件的表
it's got two main tables that we care
about it's got one table that map's file
块ID或块句柄数组的名称，这只是告诉您在哪里
name to an array of chunk IDs or chunk
handles this just tells you where to
查找数据或什么是块标识符，所以它是
find the data or what the what the
identifiers are the chunks are so it's
您还可以使用块标识符完成很多工作，但是主节点也会发生
not much yet you can do with a chunk
identifier but the master also happens
拥有第二张表，该表的块将每个块的句柄处理到一个
to have a a second table that map's
chunk handles each chunk handle to a
一堆有关该块的数据，因此是保存的块服务器列表
bunch of data about that chunk so one is
the list of chunk servers that hold
每个块的数据副本存储在一个以上的块服务器上，因此
replicas of that data each chunk is
stored on more than one chunk server so
这是一个列表块服务器，每个块都有一个当前版本号，因此
it's a list chunk servers every chunk
has a current version number so this
主人记住每个块的版本号
master has a remembers the version
number for each chunk all rights for a
块必须是顺序的，块的主块是副本之一，所以
chunk have to be sequence ooh the chunks
primary it's one of the replicas so
主人记得富块服务器是主要的，还有
master remembers the rich chunk servers
the primary and there's also that
主节点仅在最短的时间内被允许为主节点，因此主节点
primary is only allowed to be primary
for a certain least time so the master
记得到目前为止，所有东西都在RAM中了
remembers the expiration time of the
lease this stuff so far it's all in RAM
如果主人崩溃了，主人就走了，这样你就会
and the master so just be gone if the
master crashed so in order that you'd be
能够重新启动主服务器，并且不会忘记有关文件系统的所有信息
able to reboot the master and not forget
everything about the file system the
master实际上将所有这些数据存储在磁盘以及内存中，因此读取
master actually stores all of this data
on disk as well as in memory so reads
只是来自内存，但至少写入了必须
just come from memory but writes to at
least the parts of this data that had to
反映在此写入必须去磁盘，以及它实际的方式
be reflected on this writes have to go
to the disk so and the way it actually
可以管理的是，所有主服务器都在磁盘上有一个日志，
managed that is that there's all
the master has a log on disk and every
更改数据时，会将条目添加到磁盘和检查点上的日志中
time it changes the data it appends an
entry to the log on disk and checkpoint
因此，其中一些实际上需要存储在磁盘上，而事实并非如此
so some of this stuff actually needs to
be on disk and some doesn't it turns out
我在这里猜测了一点，但可以肯定的是，块句柄数组具有
I'm guessing a little bit here but
certainly the array of chunk handles has
要在磁盘上，所以我要在这里写env表示非易失性，这意味着
to be on disk and so I'm gonna write env
here for non-volatile meaning it it's
一定要反映在磁盘上的块服务器列表事实证明并没有
got to be reflected on disk the list of
chunk servers it turns out doesn't
因为主服务器重新启动会与所有块服务器对话，并询问它们
because the master if it reboots talks
to all the chunk servers and ask them
他们有什么块，所以我想这不是写到磁盘的版本
what chunks they have so this is I
imagine not written to disk the version
编号写入磁盘而不是写入磁盘的任何猜测都需要知道
number any guesses written to disk not
written to disk requires knowing how the
系统工作，我将投票写入磁盘非易失性我们可以争论
system works I'm gonna vote written to
disk non-volatile we can argue about
后来当我们谈论系统如何工作时，主要身份
that later when we talk about how system
works identity the primary it turns out
几乎没有肯定没有写到磁盘那么易失，原因是主
not almost certainly not written to disk
so volatile and the reason is the master
是um重新启动，因此忘记了，因为它易失，忘记了谁
is um reboots and forgets therefore
since it's volatile forgets who the
主要是用于一个块，它可以简单地等待第62个租约到期时间
primary is for a chunk it can simply
wait for the 62nd lease expiration time
然后，它知道绝对没有主服务器可以为此工作
and then it knows that absolutely no
primary will be functioning for this
块，然后可以安全地类似地指定其他主数据库
chunk and then it can designate a
different primary safely and similarly
租约到期的东西是易变的，这意味着无论何时文件
the lease expiration stuff is volatile
so that means that whenever a file is
用新块扩展的数据将转到下一个64兆字节边界或版本
extended with a new chunk goes to the
next 64 megabyte boundary or the version
编号更改，因为指定了新的主数据库，这意味着主数据库
number changes because the new primary
is designated that means that the master
首先必须在他的日志上附加一点记录，基本上是这样，哦，我刚刚添加了
has to first append a little record to
his log basically saying oh I just added
该文件的某某块，或者我刚刚更改了版本号，因此
a such-and-such a chunk to this file or
I just changed the version number so
每次更改时，其中之一就是需要正确写入磁盘，因此
every time I change is one of those that
needs to writes right it's disk so this
是纸上谈论的不多，但你知道
is paper doesn't talk about this
much but you know there's limits the
大师可以更改事物的速度，因为您只能写
rate at which the master can change
things because you can only write your
磁盘，但每秒多次，以及使用日志而不是日志的原因
disk however many times per second and
the reason for using a log rather than a
您知道磁盘上某种b树或哈希表的数据库是
database you know some sort of b-tree or
hash table on disk is that you can
非常有效地附加到日志，因为
append to a log very efficiently because
您只需要可以获取一堆最近的日志记录，就需要添加它们
you only need you can take a bunch of
recent log records they need to be added
并在每次旋转后一次写入就将它们全部写入
and sort of write them all on a single
write after a single rotation to
磁盘中包含日志文件结尾的任何点，而
whatever the point in the disk is that
contains the end of the log file whereas
如果它是反映该数据真实结构的b树，那么您
if it were a sort of b-tree reflecting
the real structure of this data then you
将不得不寻找磁盘中的随机位置，并做一些正确的事情，所以
would have to seek to a random place in
the disk and do a little right so the
日志的写入速度更快一些，以反映对
log makes a little bit faster to write
there to reflect operations on to the
磁盘，但是如果主机崩溃并且必须重建其状态，
disk however if the master crashes and
has to reconstruct its state you
不想从头开始重新读取其日志文件
wouldn't want to have to reread its log
file back starting from the beginning of
从几年前第一次安装服务器的时间开始，所以
time from when the server was first
installed you know a few years ago so in
另外，主服务器有时会将其完整状态检查点到磁盘
addition the master sometimes
checkpoints its complete state to disk
这需要一些时间，秒，可能是一分钟左右，然后
which takes some amount of time seconds
maybe a minute or something and then
当它重新启动时，它会返回到最新的检查点，并且
when it restarts what it does is goes
back to the most recent checkpoint and
仅播放日志中从时间点开始的部分
plays just the portion of a log that
sort of starting at the point in time
当创建检查时，有关主数据的任何问题都可以
when that check one is created any
questions about the master data okay
因此，考虑到这一点，我将列出阅读中的步骤以及
so with that in mind I'm going to lay
out the steps in a read and the steps in
所有这些前进的方向就是我
the right
where all this is heading is that I then
想讨论一下，对于每一次失败我都知道为什么
want to discuss you know for each
failure I can think of why does the
系统还是该系统在该故障之后立即采取行动，但为了做到这一点
system or does the system act directly
after that failure um but in order to do
我们需要了解数据和数据中的操作，所以如果
that we need to understand the data and
operations in the data okay so if
阅读是第一步，客户端是什么，阅读意味着
there's a read the first step is that
the client and what a read means that
该应用程序考虑了文件名，并在文件中添加了所需的偏移量
the application has a file name in mind
and an offset in the file that it wants
读取一些数据，以便将文件名和偏移量发送给主机
to read some data front so it sends the
file name and the offset to the master
然后主服务器在其文件表中查找文件名，然后您就会知道
and the master looks up the file name in
its file table and then you know each
块是64兆字节，可以使用偏移量除以64兆字节来查找
chunk is 64 megabytes who can use the
offset divided by 64 megabytes to find
哪个块，然后查看其块表中的那个块，找到列表
which chunk and then it looks at that
chunk in its chunk table finds the list
具有该数据副本并将该列表返回到
of chunk servers that have replicas of
that data and returns that list to the
客户端，所以第一步就是要知道文件名和主文件的偏移量
client so the first step is so you know
the file name and the offset the master
主机发送块句柄，假设H和服务器列表
and the master sends the chunk handle
let's say H and the list of servers so
现在我们有一些选择，我们可以要求这些服务器中的任何一个选择一个
now we have some choice we can ask any
one of these servers pick one that's and
该论文说，客户端尝试猜测哪个服务器最接近他们。
the paper says that clients try to guess
which server is closest to them in the
网络可能在同一机架中，并将读取请求发送到该副本
network maybe in the same rack and send
the read request to that to that replica
客户端实际缓存
the client actually caches
决明子的结果是，因此，如果它再次读取了该块，那么客户端
cassia's this result so that if it reads
that chunk again and indeed the client
在您知道1兆字节或64 KB片段中，可能会读取给定的块，或者
might read a given chunk in you know one
megabyte pieces or 64 kilobyte pieces or
一些东西，所以我可能最终会连续读取相同的块不同点
something so I may end up reading the
same chunk different points successive
块的多个区域，因此缓存要与您对话的服务器
regions of a chunk many times and so
caches which server to talk to you for
给块，所以它不必继续殴打主人问主人
giving chunks so it doesn't have to keep
beating on the master asking the master
一遍又一遍的相同信息
for the same information over and over
现在客户与其中一个块服务器进行对话，告诉我们一个块处理偏移量
now the client talks to one of the chunk
servers tells us a chunk handling offset
块服务器将这些块存储在每个Linux上的单独Linux文件中
and the chunk servers store these chunks
each chunk in a separate Linux file on
它们在普通Linux文件系统中的硬盘驱动器，大概是大块
their hard drive in a ordinary Linux
file system and presumably the chunk
文件仅由句柄命名，因此块服务器要做的就是去
files are just named by the handle so
all the chunk server has to do is go
找到正确名称的文件，您会知道的
find the file with the right name you
know I'll give it that
整个块，然后从该文件中读取所需的字节范围
并将数据返回给客户端我讨厌有关读取操作的问题
and return the data to the client I hate
question about how reads operate can I
重复第一个步骤，第一步是应用程序要读取它
repeat number one the step one is the
application wants to read it a
特定文件在文件特定范围内的特定偏移处
particular file at a particular offset
within the file a particular range of
文件中的字节和一千二两千，所以它只是发送一个名称
bytes in the files and one thousand two
two thousand and so it just sends a name
的文件和字节范围的开头到母版，然后
of the file and the beginning of the
byte range to the master and then the
主文件查找文件名，然后在文件表中查找包含
master looks a file name and it's file
table to find the chunk that contains
该文件的字节范围很好
that byte range for that file so good
[音乐]
[Music]
所以我不知道确切的细节，我的印象是，如果
so I don't know the exact details my
impression is that the if the
应用程序希望读取超过64兆字节甚至是两个字节，但是
application wants to read more than 64
megabytes or even just two bytes but
跨越库的边界，以便应用程序链接
spanning a chunk boundary that the
library so the applications linked with
一个将我们的个人电脑发送到各种服务器的库，该库将
a library that sends our pcs to the
various servers and that library would
请注意，读取跨越了一个大块边界，并将其分成两个单独的部分
notice that the reads spanned a chunk
boundary and break it into two separate
读书，也许和师父交谈我的意思是，也许你可以和
reads and maybe talk to the master I
mean it may be that you could talk to
主人一次，得到两个结果，但从逻辑上讲至少两个
the master once and get two results or
something but logically at least it two
向主服务器请求，然后向两个不同的块服务器请求
requests to the master and then requests
to two different chunk servers yes well
至少一开始客户端不知道给定的文件
at least initially the client doesn't
know for a given file
什么块需要什么块，它可以计算出它需要第十七个块
what chunks need what chunks well it can
calculate it needs the seventeenth chunk
但随后它需要知道哪个块服务器保存了第十七个块
but but then it needs to know what chunk
server holds the seventeenth chunk of
该文件，当然需要，它需要与
that file and for that it certainly
needs for that it needs to talk to the
师父好，所以我不会对哪个
master okay so all right did I'm not
going to make a strong claim about which
他们之中的人认为这是文件中的第17个块，但是
of them decides that it was the
seventeenth chunk in the file but it's
主机，在其中找到第十七个块的句柄的标识符
the master that finds the identifier of
the handle of the seventeenth chunk in
该文件在其表中查找并找出哪些块服务器
the file looks that up in its table and
figures out which chunk servers hold
那块是的
that chunk yes
这是什么意思？或者您的意思是，如果客户端请求的字节范围是
how does that or you mean if the if the
client asks for a range of bytes that
跨越大块边界，是的​​，所以您知道客户会问
spans a chunk boundary yeah so the the
well you know the client will ask that
与此库链接的客户端是一个注意到的GFS库
well the clients linked with this
library is a GFS library that noticed
如何将读取请求拆开并将它们放回原处
how to take read requests apart and put
them back together and so that library
会跟主人说话，主人会很好地告诉你，你知道大块
would talk to the master and the master
would tell it well well you know chunk
七个在此服务器上，块八在该服务器上，然后为什么
seven is on this server and chunk eight
is on that server and then why the
图书馆只能说哦，你知道我需要最后一口
library would just be able to say oh you
know I need the last couple bites of
块七和块头八的前几口，然后取
chunk seven and the first couple bites
of chunk eight and then would fetch
那些将它们放到缓冲区中并返回给调用应用程序
those put them together in a buffer and
return them to the calling application
好吧主人告诉它有关块和图书馆的数字
well the master tells it about chunks
and the library kind of figures out
它应该在给定的块中查找以找到应用程序日期的地方
where it should look in a given chunk to
find the date of the application wanded
该应用程序仅根据文件名和类型中的偏移量来考虑
the application only thinks in terms of
file names and sort of just offsets in
库中的整个文件和主文件合谋将其变成大块
the entire file in the library and the
master conspire to turn that into chunks
是的
yeah
抱歉，让我靠近这里，您再次看到，所以问题很重要
sorry let me get closer here you see
again so the question is does it matter
您到达房间的那台大块服务器，所以您知道是，否从概念上讲，它们都是
which chunk server you reach room so you
know yes and no notionally they're all
实际上应该是您可能已经注意到或我们将要谈论的副本
supposed to be replicas in fact as you
may have noticed or as we'll talk about
他们不是你知道他们不一定相同和应用
they're not you know they're not
necessarily identical and applications
本来应该可以忍受的，但事实是，
are supposed to be able to tolerate this
but the fact is that you make a slightly
不同的数据取决于您阅读的是，所以论文说
different data depending on which
replicas you read yeah so the paper says
客户端尝试从同一机架或同一机架上的组块服务器读取数据
that clients try to read from the chunk
server that's in the same rack or on the
相同的开关或没事的东西，所以读
same switch or something all right so
that's reads
权利现在变得更加复杂有趣
the rights are more complex and
interesting now the application
权利的界面非常相似，只是有些调用某些库
interface for rights is pretty similar
there's just some call some library you
呼叫您对gfs客户端库进行匹配，说这是一个文件名
call to mate you make to the gfs client
library saying look here's a file name
以及我要写入的字节范围和我想要的数据缓冲区
and a range of bytes I'd like to write
and the buffer of data that I'd like you
写那个范围实际上让我让我退缩我只想谈
to write to that that range actually let
me let me backpedal I only want to talk
关于笔的记录，所以我要称赞此客户端界面为
about record of pens and so I'm going to
praise this the client interface as the
客户拨打图书馆电话，说这是一个文件名，我想
client makes a library call that says
here's a file name and I'd like to
将此字节缓冲区附加到文件中，我说这是笔记录
append this buffer of bytes to the file
I said this is the record of pens that
论文再次讨论，客户问我想要的主观
the paper talks about so again the
client asks the master look I want to
追加发送一个主文件，请求我要对此命名文件进行笔操作
append sends a master requesting what I
would like to pen to this named file
请告诉我在文件中查找最后一块的位置，因为
please tell me where to look for the
last chunk in the file because the
如果许多客户对文件的意见不完整，则客户可能不知道文件有多长时间。
client may not know how long the file is
if lots of clients are opinion to the
相同的文件，因为我们有一些大文件，这记录了很多东西
same file because we have some big file
this logging stuff from a lot of
不同的客户可能是您知道没有客户一定会知道多长时间
different clients may be you know no
client will necessarily know how long
该文件是文件，因此应将其附加到哪个偏移量或哪个块中
the file is and therefore which offset
or which chunk it should be appending to
因此，您可以询问主服务器，请告诉我有关容纳该服务器的服务器的信息。
so you can ask the master please tell me
about the the server's that hold the
该文件中的最后一个当前块
very last chunk
current chunk in this file so
不幸的是，如果您正在阅读，现在可以阅读任何最新的文章。
unfortunately now the writing if you're
reading you can read from any up-to-date
用于写的副本，尽管需要有一个主副本，所以此时
replica for writing though there needs
to be a primary so at this point on the
文件可能具有也可能没有由主服务器指定的主文件，因此我们
file may or may not have a primary
already designated by the master so we
需要考虑以下情况：如果没有主节点，而所有主节点
need to consider the case of if there's
no primary already and all the master
知道没有初级，所以一个案例也不是初级
knows well there's no primary so so one
case is no primary
在这种情况下，主服务器需要找出具有以下功能的一组块服务器：
in that case the master needs to find
out the set of chunk servers that have
该块的最新副本，因为知道您是否一直在运行
the most up-to-date copy of the chunk
because know if you've been running the
系统由于故障或可能存在大块服务器而长期处于运行状态
system for a long time due to failures
or whatever there may be chunk servers
那里有你昨天或最后一次知道的大块旧副本
out there that have old copies of the
chunk from you know yesterday or last
我一直保持最新状态的一周，因为也许该服务器是
week that I've been kept up to kept up
to date because maybe that server was
死了几天，没有收到更新，所以您需要
dead for a couple days and wasn't
receiving updates so there's you need to
能够分辨出最新的块副本与非最新副本之间的区别
be able to tell the difference between
up-to-date copies of the chunk and non
是最新的，所以第一步是找到您知道的东西，找到最新的东西，这就是全部
up-to-date so the first step is to find
you know find up-to-date this is all
发生在主人身上，因为客户要求主人告诉
happening in the master because the
client has asked the master told the
主人看，我要这个文件的结尾请告诉我要使用什么块服务
master look I want up end of this file
please tell me what chunk service to
与主机的一部分进行交谈，试图找出哪些块服务器
talk to so a part of the master trying
to figure out what chunk servers the
客户应该与您联系，以便我们最终找到最新的
client should talk to you
so when we finally find up-to-date
副本，更新的意思是副本，其块的版本为
replicas and what update means is a
replica whose version of the chunk is
等于主站知道的最新版本号
equal to the version number that the
master knows is the most up-to-date
版本号是由母版分发这些版本号
version number it's the master that
hands out these version numbers the
主人记得哦，对于这个特定的块，你知道树干
master remembers that oh for this
particular chunk you know the trunk
服务器只有版本号为17的服务器才是最新的，这就是为什么它具有
server is only up to date if it has
version number 17 and this is why it has
非易失性存储在磁盘上，因为如果它在崩溃中丢失并且
to be non-volatile stored on disk
because if if it was lost in a crash and
有块服务器持有过时的副本，而主服务器则不会
there were chunk servers holding stale
copies of chunks the master wouldn't be
能够区分持有旧数据块副本的数据块服务器
able to distinguish between chunk
servers holding stale copies of a chunk
从上周开始，还有一个存储块服务器副本的块服务器
from last week and a chunk server that
holds the copy of the chunk that was
崩溃前的最新消息，这就是版本号的主要成员
up-to-date as of the crash that's why
the master members of version number on
磁盘是的
disk yeah
如果您知道自己正在与所有块服务器通信，那么观察结果是
if you knew you were talking to all the
chunk servers okay so the observation is
如果主机重新启动，主服务器无论如何都必须与块服务器通信
the master has to talk to the chunk
servers anyway if it reboots in order to
查找哪个块服务器保留哪个块，因为主服务器不
find which chunk server holds which
chunk because the master doesn't
请记住，所以您可能会认为您可以最大限度地利用自己
remember that so you might think that
you could just take the maximum you
可以与块服务器进行交谈，以了解它们的中继和版本
could just talk to the chunk servers
find out what trunks and versions they
保持并为给定块整体取最大值
hold and take the maximum for a given
chunk overall the responding chunk
服务器，并且如果所有持有块的块服务器都响应了
servers and that would work if all the
chunk servers holding a chunk responded
但风险是，在主服务器重启时，可能有一些
but the risk is that at the time the
master reboots maybe some of the chunk
服务器处于脱机状态或已断开连接，或者它们本身在重新启动并且不
servers are offline or disconnected or
whatever themselves rebooting and don't
响应，因此所有主服务器返回的都是来自块服务器的响应，这些服务器
respond and so all the master gets back
is responses from chunk servers that
拥有上周的数据块和具有当前数据块的数据块服务器的副本
have last week's copies of the block and
the chunk servers that have the current
复制尚未完成重启或脱机操作，所以还可以，如果
copy haven't finished rebooting or
offline or something so ok oh yes if if
如果您丢失了服务器，则拥有最新副本的服务器将永久失效
the server's holding the most recent
copy are permanently dead if you've lost
全部复制块的所有最新版本，然后是
all copies all of the most recent
version of a chunk then yes
不好，所以问题是师父知道
No
okay so the question is the master knows
该块正在寻找版本17
that for this chunk is looking for
version 17
假设它找不到您知道的块服务器，并且与块服务器对话
supposing it finds no chunk server you
know and it talks to the chunk servers
定期询问他们您拥有哪些区块
periodically to sort of ask them what
chunks do you have what versions you
假设它没有为此找到带有版本17的块17的服务器
have supposing it finds no server with
chunk 17 with version 17 for this this
块，那么主机将要么说好要么不响应然后等待或
chunk then the master will either say
well either not respond yet and wait or
它将告诉客户外观我无法回答，请稍后再试，这
it will tell the client look I can't
answer that try again later and this
会像建筑物断电一样出现
would come up like there was a power
failure in the building and all the
服务器崩溃，我们正在缓慢地重新启动主服务器
server's crashed and we're slowly
rebooting the master might come up first
而且您知道部分服务器可能已启动，而其他服务器可能会启动
and you know some fraction of the chunk
servers might be up and other ones would
从现在开始五分钟后重启，所以我们要求准备好等待，它将
reboot five minutes from now but so we
ask to be prepared to wait and it will
永远等待，因为您不想使用该块的陈旧版本
wait forever because you don't want to
use a stale version of that of a chunk
好的，因此主服务器需要汇编具有最大数量的块服务器的列表
okay so the master needs to assemble the
list of chunk servers that have the most
主服务器知道磁盘上存储的最新版本
recent version the master knows the most
recent versions stored on disk each
您指出的块服务器以及每个块还记得
chunk server along with each chunk as
you pointed out also remembers the
它存储的块的版本号，以便在块被分割时
version number of the chunk that it's
stores so that when chunk slivers
向大师报告说，看，我有这个块，大师可以忽略
reported into the master saying look I
have this chunk the master can ignore
版本与主站知道的版本不匹配的版本
the ones whose version does not match
the version the master knows is the most
最近还好，所以请记住我们是客户想要附加主数据的客户
recent okay so remember we were the
client want to append the master doesn't
有一个主要的数字，它可能需要等待这组数据块
have a primary it figures out maybe you
have to wait for the set of chunk
具有该块的最新版本的服务器会选择一个主服务器
servers that have the most recent
version of that chunk it picks a primary
所以我要选择其中一个作为主要，其他选择作为次要
so I'm gonna pick one of them to be the
primary and the others to be secondary
副本服务器中最多设置的服务器
servers
among the replicas set at the most
主服务器的最新版本然后递增
recent version the master then
increments
版本号并将其写入磁盘，这样就不会忘记崩溃
the version number and writes that to
disk so it doesn't forget it the crashes
然后将其发送给次要对象，而每个辅助对象
and then it sends the primary in the
secondaries and that's each of them a
消息说寻找这块是这里主要的是
message saying look for this chunk
here's the primary here's the
您知道接收者的中学可能是其中的其中之一，这是新版本
secondaries you know recipient maybe one
of them and here's the new version
数字，然后它告诉主次要信息以及
number so then it tells primary
secondaries this information plus the
主版本号和次版本号
version number the primaries and
secondaries
可以将版本号保存到磁盘，这样他们就不会忘记，因为您知道是否
alright the version number to disk so
they don't forget because you know if
发生电源故障，或者他们必须向主报告
there's a power failure or whatever they
have to report in to the master with the
他们持有的实际版本号是
actual version number they hold yes
这是一个很好的问题，所以我不知道
that's a great question
so I don't know there's hints in the
我对此略有错误的论文，所以论文说我认为你的问题
paper that I'm slightly wrong about this
so the paper says I think your question
正在向我解释有关该论文的内容
was explaining something to me about the
paper the paper says if the master
重新引导并与块服务器进行对话，并且其中一个块服务器重新引导报告
reboots and talks to chunk servers and
one of the chunk servers reboot reports
版本号高于主机记住的版本号
a version number that's higher than the
version number the master remembers the
主服务器假定在分配新的主服务器时出现故障，并且
master assumes that there was a failure
while it was assigning a new primary and
采用新的从块服务器听到的更高版本号，因此
adopts the new the higher version number
that it heard from a chunk server so it
在这种情况下，为了处理主崩溃，必须
must be the case that in order to handle
a master crash at this point that the
主机告诉主服务器之后，将自己的版本号写入磁盘
master writes its own version number to
disk after telling the primaries there's
这里有点问题，因为如果那是一个ACK
a bit of a problem here though because
if the was that is there an ACK
好吧，所以也许主人告诉初选和备份，他们
all right so maybe the master tells the
primaries and backups and that their
小学和中学，如果他们是小学告诉他新的
primaries and secondaries if they're a
primary secondary tells him the new
版本号等待AK，然后写入磁盘或不满意的内容
version number waits for the AK and then
writes to disk or something unsatisfying
关于这一点，我不认为这可行，因为
about this I don't believe that works
because of the possibility that the
具有最新版本号的块服务器在以下位置脱机
chunk servers with the most recent
version numbers being offline at the
主机重启时，我们不希望主机不知道
time the master reboots we wouldn't want
the master the master doesn't know the
当前版本号，它将仅接受遵循的最高版本号
current version number it'll just accept
whatever highest version number adheres
可能是旧版本号，所以这是我的一个区域
which could be an old version number all
right so this is a an area of my
无知我不太了解主更新系统版本
ignorance I don't really understand
whether the master update system version
首先在此编号，然后告诉主要中学或其他方式
number on this first and then tells the
primary secondary or the other way
我不确定它是否可以正常工作，但无论如何都可以，或者
around and I'm not sure it works either
way okay but in any case one way or
另一个主更新是版本号，告诉主副外观
another the master update is version
number tells the primary secondary look
您的主要和次要这是一个新版本号，所以现在我们有了一个
your primaries and secondaries here's a
new version number and so now we have a
能够接受的主要对象写的所有权限就是主要对象的工作
primary which is able to accept writes
all right that's what the primaries job
是从客户那里获取权利，并组织将这些权利应用于
is to take rights from clients and
organize applying those rights to the
各种块服务器，您知道版本号的原因是
various chunk servers and you know the
reason for the version number stuff is
这样主人就能认出
so that the master will recognize the
哪些服务器具有此新功能，您知道
which servers have this new you know the
大师向我们希望成为某些块服务器的主要角色
master hands out the ability to be
primary for some chunk server we want to
能够识别出主机是否崩溃，您知道那是
be able to recognize if the master
crashes you know that it was that was
主要的，只有那个主要的，实际上是次要的
the primary that only that primary and
it secondaries which were actually
处理的是负责更新只有那些
processed which were in charge of
updating that chunk that only those
将来可以将主服务器和辅助服务器作为块服务器，并且
primaries and secondaries are allowed to
be chunk servers in the future and the
主机使用此版本号逻辑的方式
way the master does this is with this
version number logic
好吧，师父告诉小学和中学，他们在那里
okay so the master tells the primaries
and secondaries that there it they're
允许修改此块，它还为主要对象提供了租约
allowed to modify this block it also
gives the primary a lease which
基本上告诉您在接下来的60年里您是主要人物的主要外观
basically tells the primary look you're
allowed to be primary for the next sixty
六十秒后几秒钟，您必须停下来，这是机械的一部分
seconds after sixty Seconds you have to
stop and this is part of the machinery
为了确保我们不会以两个原语结束，我会说一些
for making sure that we don't end up
with two primaries I'll talk about a bit
后来好了，所以现在我们是主要的，主人告诉客户
later okay so now we were primary now
the master tells the client who the
主要和次要沙皇，此时我们正在执行
primary and the secondary czar and at
this point we're we're executing in
图二，客户现在知道谁是主要中学
figure two in the paper the client now
knows who the primary secondaries are in
某种顺序或另一种顺序，论文解释了一种聪明的管理方式
some order or another and the paper
explains a sort of clever way to manage
客户端以某种顺序或其他顺序发送它想要的数据副本
this in some order or another the client
sends a copy of the data it wants to be
附加到所有次级中的主要节点上，并附加到
appended to the primary in all the
secondaries and the primary in the
辅助节点将该数据写入未附加到的临时位置
secondaries write that data to a
temporary location it's not appended to
他们都说是之后的文件，但我们有客户发送的数据
the file yet after they've all said yes
we have the data the client sends a
传达给主要语录的信息，您知道您和所有辅助语录都有
message to the primary saying look you
know you and all the secondaries have
我要附加到此文件的数据
the data I'd like to append it for this
file
主要可能是从许多不同的客户那里收到这些请求
the primary maybe is receiving these
requests from lots of different clients
同时它选择一些命令一次执行一个客户请求
concurrently it picks some order execute
the client request one at a time and for
每个客户笔请求主笔看一下偏移量的结尾
each client a pen request the primary
looks at the offset that's the end of
该文件，当前块的当前结尾确保有足够的空间
the file the current end of the current
chunk makes sure there's enough
块中的剩余空间，然后告诉然后将客户记录写入
remaining space in the chunk and then
tells then writes the clients record to
当前块的末尾，并告诉所有次要对象也要编写
the end of the current chunk and tells
all the secondaries to also write the
客户端数据的末尾相同偏移量在块中相同偏移量
clients data to the end to the same
offset the same offset in their chunks
好的，所以主数据库选择一个偏移量，包括主数据库在内的所有副本
all right so the primary picks an offset
all the replicas including the primary
被告知在偏移处写入新的附加记录。
are told to write
the new appended record at at offset the
中学的，他们可能会做，他们可能不会做，我要么空间不足，要么
secondary's they may do it they may not
do it I'm either run out of space maybe
他们崩溃了，也许网络消息从主数据库丢失了，所以如果
they crashed maybe the network message
was lost from the primary so if a
辅助服务器实际上将数据以该偏移量写入其磁盘，它将对
secondary actually wrote the data to its
disk at that offset it will reply yes to
如果主数据库从所有辅助数据库收集是的答案，则是主数据库
the primary if the primary collects a
yes answer from all of the secondaries
因此，如果所有人都设法写出并回复主
so if they all of all of them managed to
actually write and reply to the primary
说是的，我做到了，然后主要的将回复成功的答复
saying yes I did it then the primary is
going to reply reply success to the
客户端，如果主服务器没有从其中一台服务器获得答案，或者
client if the primary doesn't get an
answer from one of the secondaries or
次要回复抱歉，发生了一些不好的事情，我的磁盘空间不足
the secondary reply sorry something bad
happened I ran out of disk space my disk
我不知道主要代表对客户和文件的答复是什么
I don't know what then the primary
replies no to the client and the paper
说哦，如果客户端在主服务器上收到类似的错误，
says oh if the client gets an error like
that back in the primary the client is
应该重新发出整个追加序列，然后再次与
supposed to reissue the entire append
sequence starting again talking to the
大师找出文件末尾的油脂最多
master to find out the most grease the
chunk at the end of the file
我想知道客户应该重新发布整个记录追加
I want to know the client supposed to
reissue the whole record append
操作啊，你会想的，但他们没有，所以问题是你知道
operation ah you would think but they
don't so the question is jeez you know
主要的告诉所有的副本都做追加，也许是其中的一些
the the primary tells all the replicas
to do the append yeah maybe some of them
如果其中一些不正确，那么其中一些不正确，那么我们
do some of them don't
right if some of them don't then we
向客户端应用错误，以便客户端认为追加发生
apply an error to the client so the
client thinks of the append in happen
但是那些笔成功的其他复制品确实附加了，所以现在我们有了
but those other replicas where the pen
succeeded they did append so now we have
复制供体相同的数据，其中一个返回错误，但没有做
replicas donor the same data one of them
the one that returned in error didn't do
追加和他们返回的是的确实做了追加，所以只是
the append and the ones they returned
yes did do the append so that is just
GFS的工作方式
the way GFS works
是的，因此，如果读者随后读取此文件，则取决于它们是什么副本
yeah so if a reader then reads this file
they depending on what replica they be
他们可能会看到附加的记录，或者可能会看到附加的记录
they may either see the appended record
or they may not if the record append
但是如果记录追加成功，则客户端返回了成功消息
but if the record append succeeded if
the client got a success message back
那么这意味着所有复制品都以相同的偏移量附加了该记录
then that means all of the replicas
appended that record at the same offset
如果客户端没有退款，则零个或多个副本可能具有
if the client gets a no back then zero
or more of the replicas may have
附加了所有记录的集合，而其他记录则没有，因此客户可以
appended the record of that all set and
the other ones not so the client got to
然后知道，这意味着某些副本也许某些副本具有记录，
know then that means that some replicas
maybe some replicas have the record and
有些人则不这么认为，您大致了解到的内容可能是
some don't so what you which were
roughly read from you know you may or
可能看不到记录是的
may not see the record yeah
哦，所有副本都是相同的，所有第二副本都是相同的版本
oh that all the replicas are the same
all the secondaries are the same version
号，因此版本号仅在主服务器分配新的时才更改
number so the version number only
changes when the master assigns a new
通常会发生，并且可能只有在主要
primary which would ordinarily happen
and probably only happen if the primary
失败了，所以我们要谈论的是具有新版本的副本
failed so what we're talking about is is
replicas that have the fresh version
没事，看着他们就看不出来
number all right and you can't tell from
looking at them that they're missing
副本是不同的，但也许它们是不同的，并且
that the replicas are different but
maybe they're different and the
这样做的理由是，是的，您知道复制品可能不都具有
justification for this is that yeah you
know maybe the replicas don't all have
附加的记录，但主要回答是
that the appended record but that's the
case in which the primary answer no to
客户端和客户端知道写入失败及其原因
the clients and the client knows that
the write failed and the reasoning
这是因为客户端库将重新发出附加内容，因此
behind this is that then the client
library will reissue the append so the
附加记录将显示出来，您知道最终Pendel会成功
appended record will show up you know
eventually the a pendel succeed you
会认为，因为客户端，我会继续发行它，直到成功，然后
would think because the client I'll keep
reissuing it until succeeds and then
当它成功时，这意味着会有一些抵消，您将进一步了解
when it succeeds that means there's
gonna be some offset you know farther on
该记录实际上出现在所有副本中的文件中
in the file where that record actually
occurs in all the replicas as well as
该单词之前的偏移量仅在少数副本中出现
offsets preceding that word only occurs
in a few of the replicas yes
哦，这是一个很好的问题，正确数据所采用的确切路径
oh this is a great question
the exact path that the right data takes
对于基础网络和本文而言可能非常重要
might be quite important with respect to
the underlying network and the paper
某处说，即使当论文第一次谈到它时，他声称
somewhere says even though when the
paper first talks about it he claims
客户端实际上在稍后将数据发送到每个副本时会更改
that the client sends the data to each
replica in fact later on it changes the
调整并说客户端仅将其发送到最接近的副本，然后
tune and says the client sends it to
only the closest of the replicas and
然后副本然后那个副本将数据转发到另一个副本
then the replicas then that replica
forwards the data to another replica
直到所有副本都有数据和该路径为止
along I sort of chained until all the
replicas had the data and that path of
该链被用来最大程度地减少交换机之间的交叉瓶颈
that chain is taken to sort of minimize
crossing bottleneck inter switch links
在数据中心中，仅当主服务器
in a data center yes the version number
only gets incremented if the master
认为没有小学，所以在普通顺序中已经有小学了
thinks there's no primary so it's a so
in the ordinary sequence there already
成为那个块的主要对象，主人会记住的哦
be a primary for that chunk the the
the the master sort of will remember oh
天哪，该块已经有一个主要和次要的，它只是
gosh there's already a primary and
secondary for that chunk and it'll just
它不会通过此主选择，不会增加版本
it won't go through this master
selection it won't increment the version
数字，它只会告诉客户查找这是没有
number it'll just tell the client look
up here's the primary with with no
版本号变更
version number change
我的理解是，如果是这样，我想你是在问一个
my understanding is that if this is this
I think you're asking a you're asking an
有趣的问题，所以在这种情况下，没有答案的原色
interesting question so in this scenario
in which the primaries isn't answered
对客户的失败，您可能会认为某些事情一定有问题
failure to the client you might think
something must be wrong with something
并且据我所知，应该在实际操作之前先将其修复
and that it should be fixed before you
proceed in fact as far as I can tell the
纸张没有立即发生的任何事情，客户会重试您知道的追加
paper there's no immediate anything the
client retries the append you know
因为也许问题是网络消息丢失了，所以没有什么可做的
because maybe the problem was a network
message got lost so there's nothing to
维修权，您知道，现在我们将丢失消息，我们应该
repair right you know now we're gonna
message got lost we should be
传输，这是一种复杂的传输方式
transmitted and this is sort of a
complicated way of retransmitting the
在这种情况下，网络消息也许是最常见的故障类型
network message maybe that's the most
common kind of failure in that case just
我们没有改变任何东西，它仍然是客户相同的主要相同的次要
we don't change anything it's still the
same primary same secondaries the client
我们尝试这次可能会成功，因为网络无法正常运行
we tries maybe this time it'll work
because the network doesn't
丢弃消息，这是一个有趣的问题，如果出了什么问题
discard a message it's an interesting
question though that if what went wrong
这是其中之一存在严重错误或故障
here is that one of that there was a
serious error or Fault in one of the
二级服务器我们希望主机重新配置该组
secondaries what we would like is for
the master to reconfigure that set of
复制副本以删除不起作用的辅助节点，这将是因为
replicas to drop that secondary that's
not working and it would then because
在执行此代码路径时选择一个新的主节点
it's choosing a new primary in executing
this code path the master would then
增加版本，然后我们有一个新的主要和新的工作辅助
increment the version and then we have a
new primary and new working secondaries
具有新版本，而次要版本具有旧版本和
with a new version and this not-so-great
secondary with an old version and a
数据的陈旧副本，但是因为它具有旧版本，所以主服务器永远不会
stale copy of the data but because that
has an old version the master will never
永远不要误以为它是新鲜的，但论文中没有证据表明
never mistake it for being fresh but
there's no evidence in the paper that
只要客户说的话，这种情况就会立即发生
that happens immediately as far as
what's said in the paper the client just
重试，并希望以后可以再次使用，如果
retries and hopes it works again later
eventually the master will if the
中学死了，最终主人完成了对所有
secondary is dead
eventually the master does ping all the
中继服务器将意识到这一点，然后可能会更改
trunk servers will realize that and will
probably then change the set of
小学和中学，并增加版本，但仅在以后
primaries and secondaries and increment
the version but only only later
问题的答案主人是否认为租赁的租赁
the lease the leases that the answer to
the question what if the master thinks
主要是死了，因为它无法达到正确的水平，这假设我们在
the primary is dead because it can't
reach it right that's supposing we're in
在某种程度上，主人说你是主要的，
a situation where at some point the
master said you're the primary and the
师父就像定期给他们粉刷所有服务，看他们是否
master was like painting them all the
service periodically to see if they're
之所以活着，是因为如果他们死了并且想要选择一个新的主要孩子
alive because if they're dead and wants
to pick a new primary the master sends
对您的一些ping操作是您的主要操作，您没有正确回应，因此您会
some pings to you you're the primary and
you don't respond right so you would
认为当时您没有回应我的ping
think that at that point where gosh
you're not responding to my pings then
您可能会认为此时的主节点将指定一个新的主节点
you might think the master at that point
would designate a new primary it turns
指出这本身就是一个错误，原因在于它是一个错误
out that by itself is a mistake and the
reason for that the reason why it's a
做那个简单的错误，你知道吗？使用那个简单的设计是我可能
mistake to do that simple did you know
use that simple design is that I may be
ping通您，而我没有得到回复的原因是因为
pinging you and the reason why I'm not
getting responses is because then
我和您之间的网络有问题，所以有一个
there's something wrong with a network
between me and you so there's a
你还活着的可能性你是你活着的主要我在撒尿你
possibility that you're alive you're the
primary you're alive I'm peeing you the
网络正在丢弃该数据包，但您可以与其他客户端进行通讯，
network is dropping that packets but you
can talk to other clients and you're
服务从您知道的其他客户的请求，如果我是我的主人
serving requests from other clients you
know and if I if I the master sort of
为该块指定了一个新的主数据库，现在我们要处理两个主数据库
designated a new primary for that chunk
now we'd have two primaries processing
权利，但有两个不同的数据副本，所以现在我们完全可以
rights but two different copies of the
data and so now we have totally
分歧复制数据，这就是所谓的具有两个原语的错误
diverging copies the data and that's
called that error having two primaries
或其他不知道彼此的处理请求称为鱿鱼
or whatever processing requests without
knowing each other it's called squid
脑子，我在船上写这个，因为这是一个重要的想法，
brain and I'm writing this on board
because it's an important idea and it'll
再次出现是由网络引起的，或者通常是由网络引起的
come up again and it's caused or it's
usually said to be caused by network
某些网络错误的分区，主服务器无法与之通信
partition that is some network error in
which the master can't talk to the
主服务器，但主服务器可以与客户端进行部分网络故障对话
primary but the primary can talk to
clients sort of partial network failure
而且您知道这些是其中最难处理的问题
and you know these are some of the these
are the hardest problems to deal with
并建立这类存储系统就可以了，这就是我们
and building these kind of storage
systems okay so that's the problem is we
还要排除错误指定的可能性
want to rule out the possibility of
mistakingly designating too
我是白羊座的主人，实现目标的方式是
I'm Aries for the same chunk the way the
master achieves that is that when it
指定一个主要的，说它提供一个主要的Elyse，基本上
designates a primary it says it gives a
primary Elyse which is basically the
主人有权在一定时间内知道自己记忆并知道的主要权利
right to be primary until a certain time
the master knows it remembers and knows
最小持续多长时间，主要群体知道，如果最小持续多久
how long the least lasts and the primary
knows how long is least lasts if the
租约到期，主要服务器知道它已到期，并且只会停止执行
lease expires the primary knows that it
expires and will simply stop executing
客户请求它将在租约到期后忽略或拒绝客户请求
client requests it'll ignore or reject
client requests after the lease expired
因此，如果主人无法与小学生交谈，而主人希望
and therefore if the master can't talk
to the primary and the master would like
为了指定新的主服务器，主服务器必须等待租约到期
to designate a new primary the master
must wait for the lease to expire for
以前的主要对象，这意味着师父将坐下来
the previous primary so that means
master is going to sit on its hands for
一个租约期60秒后，可以保证旧的主要租期
one lease period 60 seconds after that
it's guaranteed the old primary will
停止操作其主要服务器，现在主机可以看到他是否不需要新主机
stop operating its primary and now the
master can see if he doesn't need a new
没有产生这种可怕的裂脑情况的原发性
primary without producing this terrible
split brain situation
哦，所以问题是为什么自客户以来就被指定为新的主要不良产品
oh so the question is why is designated
a new primary bad since the clients
总是先问主人，所以主人改变主意，然后再改变
always ask the master first and so the
master changes its mind then subsequent
客户会将客户导向新的主要井井，原因之一是
clients will direct the clients to the
new primary well one reason is that the
客户兑现以提高效率客户兑现主要银行的身份
clients cash for efficiency the clients
cash the identity of the primary for at
至少在短时间内，即使他们没有，尽管坏序列是
least for short periods of time even if
they didn't though the bad sequence is
我是主要的主人你问我主要的是谁我给你发消息
that I'm the prime the master you ask me
who the primary is I send you a message
说主要是服务器一项权利，并且该消息在
saying the primary is server one right
and that message is inflate in the
网络，然后我是主人我知道我认为有人失败了
network and then I'm the master I you
know I think somebody's failed whatever
我认为小学已满，我指定了一个新小学，然后将
I think that primary is filled I
designated a new primary and I send the
主要消息说你是主要的，我开始回答其他
primary message saying you're the
primary and I start answering other
询问主要客户的客户说那边是主要客户
clients who ask the primary is saying
that that over there is the primary
当发送给您的消息仍在传播时，您会收到消息说
while the message to you is still in
flight you receive the message saying
老小学，你以为是小学，我刚从大师那里得到
the old primaries the primary you think
gosh I just got this from the master I'm
会去和那个主要学生交谈，而没有一些更聪明的计划
gonna go talk to that primary and
without some much more clever scheme
即使您刚得到这个，也无法意识到
there's no way you could realize that
even though you just got this
来自主服务器的信息已经过时，如果该主服务器
information from the master it's already
out of date and if that primary serves
您的修改请求现在我们必须正确响应您的要求
your modification requests now we have
to and and respond success to you right
那么我们有两个相互冲突的副本
then we have two conflicting replicas
是
yes
再次，您有一个新文件，没有副本，所以如果您有一个新文件，
again you've a new file and no replicas
okay so if you have a new file no
复制品，甚至是现有文件，但没有复制品，您将采用我绘制的路径
replicas or even an existing file and no
replicas the you'll take the path I drew
在黑板上，主人会收到客户的要求，说
on the blackboard the master will
receive a request from a client saying
哦，我想附加到这个文件，然后我想大师会先
oh I'd like to append to this file and
then well I guess the master will first
看到没有与该文件相关的数据块，它将组成一个新的
see there's no chunks associated with
that file and it will just make up a new
块标识符或通过调用随机数生成器，然后
chunk identifier or perhaps by calling
the random number generator and then
它会在它的块信息表中查看，天哪，我没有任何
it'll look in its chunk information
table and see gosh I don't have any
有关该块的信息，它将组成一条新记录，但必须
information about that chunk and it'll
make up a new record saying but it must
是特殊情况的代码，它说得很好，我不知道任何版本号
be special case code where it says well
I don't know any version number this
块不存在，我只是要组成一个新版本号
chunk doesn't exist I'm just gonna make
up a new version number one pick a
随机设置主要和次要对象，并告诉他们您负责
random primary and set of secondaries
and tell them look you are responsible
对于这个新的空块，请开始工作，该文件说每个副本三个
for this new empty chunk please get to
work the paper says three replicas per
默认情况下为大块，因此通常是主备份和两个备份
chunk by default so typically a primary
and two backups
好吧好吧，所以也许最重要的就是重复
okay okay so the maybe the most
important thing here is just to repeat
我们几分钟前的讨论
the discussion we had a few minutes ago
GFS的有意构建是为了让我们记录这些笔，如果我们
the intentional construction of GFS we
had these record a pens is that if we
有三个，我们有三个副本，您可能知道一个客户端发送了一个副本
have three we have three replicas you
know maybe a client sends in and a
记录一支笔以记录a和所有三个副本或主要副本和两个副本
record a pen for record a and all three
replicas or the primary and both of the
次要对象成功地将数据附加到块中，也可能是第一个记录中
secondaries successfully append the data
the chunks and maybe the first record in
在这种情况下，树干可能是一个，他们都同意，因为他们都做到了
the trunk might be a in that case and
they all agree because they all did it
假设另一个客户进来，说我要笔记录B，但是
supposing another client comes in says
look I want a pen record B but the
消息丢失给网络的任何副本之一
message is lost to one of the replicas
the network whatever supposably the
消息错误，但其他两个副本获得消息，其中一个
message by mistake but the other two
replicas get the message and one of
他们是主要的，我的其他次要的，它们都依赖于文件
them's a primary and my other
secondaries they both depend of the file
所以现在我们有两个B的副本，另一个没有
so now what we have is two the replicas
that B and the other one doesn't have
任何东西，然后可能是第三个客户想要附加C，也许记住
anything and then may be a third client
wants to append C and maybe the remember
因为这是主要的，所以主要的选择了偏移量
that this is the primary the primary
picks the offset since the primary just
会告诉二级服务器在此时的正确记录C中
块他们好吧C现在这里的客户端是客户端的规则
chunk they all right C here now the
client for be the rule for a client for
B对于让我们从请求中返回错误的客户端来说，它将
B that for the client that gets us error
back from its request is that it will
重新发送请求，因此现在要求追加记录B的客户端将询问
resend the request so now the client
that asked to append record B will ask
再次到笔记录B，这一次也许没有网络损失，所有
again to a pen record B and this time
maybe there's no network losses and all
三个副本作为面板记录是正确的，它们都在那里生活，我会
three replicas as a panel record be
right and they're all lives there I'll
具有最新的版本号，现在，如果客户端读取
have the most fresh version number and
now if a client reads
他们所看到的取决于轨道
what they see depends on the track which
他们所看到的副本将总共看到所有三个记录，但是它将
replicas they look at it's gonna see in
total all three of the records but it'll
以不同的顺序查看，具体取决于哪个副本读取它，这意味着我将看到
see in different orders depending on
which replica reads it'll mean I'll see
一个BC，然后是B的重复，因此，如果读取此副本，它将看到B，然后
a B C and then a repeat of B so if it
reads this replica it'll see B and then
C如果读取此副本，它将在文件中看到a和一个空白
C if it reads this replica it'll see a
and then a blank space in the file
填充，然后是C，然后是B，所以如果您在这里阅读，则可以看到C，然后是B，如果您阅读
padding and then C and then B so if you
read here you see C then B if you read
在这里您看到的是B，然后是C，所以不同的读者会看到不同的结果，
here you see B and then C so different
readers will see different results and
也许最坏的情况是某些客户从
maybe the worst situation is it some
client gets an error back from the
主要，因为其中一名中学未能执行追加，然后
primary because one of the secondaries
failed to do the append and then the
客户在我们发送请求之前死亡，因此您可能会收到
client dies before we sending the
request so then you might get a
您的记录D出现在某些副本中的情况，并且
situation where you have record D
showing up in some of the replicas and
完全不会出现在其他副本的任何地方，所以您知道
completely not showing up anywhere in
the other replicas so you know under
这个方案对于主服务器发回一个
this scheme we have good properties for
for appends that the primary sent back a
成功的答案，对于附加项，不是那么好的属性
successful answer for and sort of not so
great properties for appends where the
主要发送回故障，并且记录副本绝对是
primary sent back of failure and the
records the replicas just absolutely be
不同的所有不同副本集是
different all different sets of replicas
yes
我在论文中读到的是，客户始于
my reading in the paper is that the
client starts at the very beginning of
的过程，并再次询问主文件，这个文件中的最后一块是什么
the process and asked the master again
what's the last chunk in this file you
知道，因为如果其他人正在处理中，则可能已更改
know because it might be might have
changed if other people are pending in
该文件是
the file yes
所以我不知道我看不懂设计师的想法，所以观察是
so I can't you know I can't read the
designers mind so the observation is the
系统本来可以使副本保持精确同步，
system could have been designed to keep
the replicas in precise sync it's
绝对正确，您将在实验2和3中进行操作，所以你们要
absolutely true and you will do it in
labs 2 & 3 so you guys are going to
设计一个进行复制的系统，该复制实际上使副本保持同步
design a system that does replication
that actually keeps the replicas in sync
然后您将了解到您知道有多种技巧
and you'll learn you know there's some
various techniques various things you
为此必须要做的事情之一，其中之一就是
have to do in order to do that and one
of them is that there just has to be
如果您希望副本保持同步，则必须遵循以下规则：
this rule if you want the replicas to
stay in sync it has to be this rule that
您不能将这些部分操作仅应用于某些操作，而不能应用于
you can't have these partial operations
that are applied to only some and not
其他的，这意味着必须有某种机制来喜欢
others and that means that there has to
be some mechanism to like where the
即使客户死亡，系统也会说我们不在那儿等一会
system even if the client dies where the
system says we don't wait a minute there
我还没有完成此操作，所以您构建的系统中
was this operation I haven't finished it
yet so you build systems in which the
主要实际上确保备份得到每条消息
primary actually make sure the backups
get every message
如果第一个正确的阿比（Abhi）失败，您认为大海应该与啤酒同行
if the first right abhi failed you think
the sea should go with the beers
好吧，您可能不认为应该，但是系统实际运行的方式
well it doesn't you may think it should
but the way the system actually operates
是主要的将C添加到块的末尾，之后V是
is that the primary will add C to the
end of the chunk and the after V yeah I
意味着这样做的原因之一是，当正确的珀西进来时，
mean one reason for this is that at the
time the right Percy comes in the
小学也许真的不知道B的命运，因为我们遇到了多个
primary may not actually know what the
fate of B was because we met multiple
客户同时提交笔，并且您知道高性能
clients submitting a pen's concurrently
and you know for high performance you
希望主要的人首先开始为B追加，然后尽快
want the primary to start the append for
B first and then as soon as I can got
下一站将告诉大家您看到了什么，以便所有这些事情发生在
the next stop set tell everybody did you
see so that all this stuff happens in
通过减慢速度，您可以知道主要的
parallel you know by slowing it down you
could you know the primary could sort of
决定B完全失败，然后发送另一轮消息说
decide that B it totally failed and then
send another round of messages saying
请撤消B的权利，这样会更复杂，更慢
please undo the right of B and there'll
be more complex and slower I'm you know
同样，这样做的理由是设计非常简单
again the the justification for this is
that the design is pretty simple it you
知道它给应用程序揭示了一些奇怪的东西，希望是
know it reveals some odd things to
applications and the hope was that
可以相对容易地编写应用程序以容忍其中的记录
applications could be relatively easily
written to tolerate records being in
不同的订单或谁知道什么，或者他们不知道该应用程序可以
different orders or who knows what or if
they couldn't that applications could
要么自己安排自己挑选订单并写信
either make their own arrangements for
picking an order themselves and writing
您知道文件中的序号或其他内容，或者如果
you know sequence numbers in the files
or something or you could just have a if
应用程序对订单非常敏感，您可能无法并发
application really was very sensitive to
order you could just not have concurrent
取决于不同的客户端到同一个文件，就可以知道
depends from different clients to the
same file right you could just you know
关闭顺序非常重要的文件，例如说它是电影文件
close files where order is very
important like say it's a movie file you
知道您不想在电影文件中加扰字节，只需编写
know you don't want to scramble
bytes in a movie file you just write the
模拟文件，您由一个客户端按顺序将电影写入文件
Moot file you write the movie to the
file by one client in sequential order
而不是同时记录取决于
and not with concurrent record depends
好的，基本上有人问
okay all right
the somebody asked basically what would
要将这种设计转变为实际上提供强大功能的设计
it take to turn this design into one
which actually provided strong
一致性一致性更接近我们的单服务器模型，其中
consistency consistency closer to our
sort of single server model where
我实际上不知道没有惊喜，因为您知道这需要
there's no surprises I don't actually
know because you know that requires an
整个新的复杂设计尚不清楚如何将GFS更改为该设计，但
entire new complex design it's not clear
how to mutate GFS to be that design but
我可以为您列出一些您想考虑的事情
I can list for you lists for you some
things that you would want to think
关于您是否想将GFS升级到帮助确实具有很强的一致性
about if you wanted to upgrade GFS to a
assistance did have strong consistency
一个是您可能需要主数据库来检测重复的请求，因此
one is that you probably need the
primary to detect duplicate requests so
当第二秒进入小学阶段时，您会意识到哦，实际上您
that when this second becomes in the
primary is aware that oh actually you
知道我们早些时候已经看到了该请求，并做了或没有做，并尝试
know we already saw that request earlier
and did it or didn't do it and to try to
确保B在文件中不会出现两次，所以您将需要一个
make sure that B doesn't show up twice
in the file so one is you're gonna need
如果辅助服务器正在执行重复检测，则可能会引起另一个问题
duplicate detection another issues you
probably if a secondary is acting a
次要的，您真的需要设计系统，以便如果主要的告诉
secondary you really need to design the
system so that if the primary tells a
中学做某事中学实际上做
secondary to do something
the secondary actually does it and
对于具有
doesn't just return error right for a
strictly consistent system having the
次要人员能够完全取消主要请求，而实际上没有
secondaries be able to just sort of blow
off primary requests with really no
赔偿金不好，所以我认为中学必须接受要求，
compensation is not okay so I think the
secondaries have to accept requests and
执行它们，或者如果辅助磁盘具有某种永久性损坏，例如磁盘
execute them or if a secondary has some
sort of permanent damage like it's disk
被误拔掉了，这需要一种机制来像
got unplugged by mistake this you need
to have a mechanism to like take the
辅助系统，因此主要系统可以继续处理剩余的系统
secondary out of the system so the
primary can proceed with the remaining
次要的，但GFS至少不会立即消失
secondaries but GFS kind of doesn't
either at least not right away
所以这也意味着当主要的要求辅助的追加
and so that also means that when the
primary asks secondary's to append
次要人员必须注意不要将数据暴露给
something the secondaries have to be
careful not to expose that data to
读者，直到主要读者确信所有次要读者确实能够
readers until the primary is sure that
all the secondaries really will be able
执行附加操作，因此您可能需要在多个阶段中
to execute the append so you might need
sort of multiple phases in the rights of
第一阶段，小学阶段要求中学阶段，你知道我真的
first phase in which the primary asks
the secondaries look you know I really
像您一样执行此操作，您可以执行此操作，但实际上尚未执行此操作
like you to do this operation can you do
it but don't don't actually do it yet
如果所有次要人员都答应能够进行手术
and if all the secondaries answer with a
promise to be able to do the operation
只有那时，主要学生说好，每个人都去做那个手术
only then the primary says alright
everybody go ahead and do that operation
你答应过的，你认识的人，这就是许多现实世界系统的方式
you promised and people you know that's
the way a lot of real world systems
强大且一致的系统正常工作，而这种技巧称为两阶段提交
strong consistent systems work and that
trick it's called two-phase commit
另一个问题是，如果主要的崩溃，将会有一些最后的崩溃
another issue is that if the primary
crashes there will have been some last
主要人员开始向次要人员发起的一组操作，但
set of operations that the primary had
launched started to the secondaries but
在确定所有这些辅助系统都没有得到之前，主要系统崩溃了
the primary crashed before it was sure
whether those all the secondaries got
那里是否复制了操作，所以如果主数据库崩溃，您会知道一个新的
there copied the operation or not so if
the primary crashes you know a new
小学中的一个将要接任小学，但是
primary one of the secondaries is going
to take over as primary but at that
指出第二个新的主要和其他次要可能不同
point the second the new primary and the
remaining secondaries may differ in the
最后几次操作，因为也许其中一些操作之前没有收到消息
last few operations because maybe some
of them didn't get the message before
主要崩溃，因此新的入门必须明确地开始
the primary crashed and so the new
primer has to start by explicitly
与次要对象重新同步，以确保
resynchronizing with the secondaries to
make sure that the sort of the tail of
他们的经营历史是一样的
their operation histories are the same
终于要解决这个问题了哦，您知道有时候
finally to deal with this problem of oh
you know there may be times when the
次要对象有所不同，或者客户可能会从
secondaries differ or the client may
have a slightly stale indication from
与系统对话的辅助节点的主节点要么需要发送所有
the master of which secondary to talk to
the system either needs to send all
客户端读取主要数据库，因为只有主要数据库才可能知道哪个
client reads through the primary because
only the primary is likely to know which
操作确实发生了，或者我们需要最少的系统来进行第二次
operations have really happened or we
need a least system for the secondaries
就像我们为小学学生准备的一样，因此众所周知
just like we have for the primary so
that it's well understood that when
佳能公司无法合法地回应客户，所以这些就是我
secondary Canon can't legally respond
a client and so these are the things I'm
意识到必须在此系统中解决该问题，以增加复杂性，
aware of that would have to be fixed in
this system tor added complexity and
使其具有很强的一致性，而实际上您就是这样
chitchat to make it have strong
consistency and you're actually the way
我得到这份清单是通过考虑您将要完成的所有实验室
I got that list was by thinking about
the labs you're gonna end up doing all
我刚刚在实验二和实验三中谈到的东西
the things I just talked about as part
of labs two and three to build a
严格一致的系统，好吧，让我花一分钟的时间
strictly consistent system okay so let
me spend one minute on there's actually
我在笔记中链接到某种回顾性访谈，内容涉及效果如何
I have a link in the notes to a sort of
retrospective interview about how well
GFS在Google生涯的前五年或十年中表现出色，因此
GFS played out over the first five or
ten years of his life at Google so the
高层次的总结是，最重要的是取得了巨大的成功，
high-level summary is that the most is
that was tremendously successful and
许多Google应用程序在许多Google基础架构中都使用了它
many many Google applications used it in
a number of Google infrastructure was
像大文件一样晚建，例如BigTable，我的意思是
built as a late like big file for
example BigTable I mean was built as a
在Google广泛使用的GFS和MapReduce之上的第二层可能是
layer on top of GFS and MapReduce also
so widely used within Google may be the
最严重的限制是只有一个主控，而主控有
most serious limitation is that there
was a single master and the master had
每个块中的每个文件都有一个表项，并且男人来做GFS
to have a table entry for every file in
every chunk and that men does the GFS
使用量增加，并且它们所包含的文件越来越多，而主文件刚耗尽
use grew and they're about more and more
files the master just ran out of memory
用完RAM来存储文件，您知道可以放更多RAM，但是
ran out of RAM to store the files and
you know you can put more RAM on but
一台机器可以拥有多少RAM是有限的，所以这就是
there's limits to how much RAM a single
machine can have and so that was the
大多数最紧迫的问题除了人们的负担
most of the most immediate problem
people ran into in addition the load on
来自成千上万客户的一个大师开始在
a single master from thousands of
clients started to be too much in the
主内核，他们看看您是否只能处理数百个
master kernel they see if you can only
process however many hundreds of
每秒的请求量，特别是磁盘上的正确内容，很快就可以得到
requests per second especially the right
things to disk and pretty soon there got
成为太多客户某些应用程序的另一个问题发现很难
to be too many clients another problem
with a some applications found it hard
处理这种奇怪的语义，最后一个问题是
to deal with this kind of sort of odd
semantics and a final problem is that
不是自动故障转移主机的主机
the master that was not an automatic
story for master failover
就像我们需要人工干预时一样
in the original in the GFS paper as we
read it like required human intervention
与曾经永久崩溃的大师打交道，需要
to deal with a master that had sort of
permanently crashed and needs to be
更换，可能要花几十分钟或更长时间，我的时间太长了
replaced and that could take tens of
minutes or more I was just too long for
某些应用程序的故障恢复好极了，我星期四见
failure recovery for some applications
okay excellent I'll see you on Thursday
在整个学期中，我们将听到更多关于所有这些主题的信息
and we'll hear more about all these
themes over the semester